Pierre Petitpas

Schönhauser Allee 140 A, Berlin, 10437 | +49 (1) 76 41 734941 | petitpaspierre@live.com

Profile

I am an experienced Scrum Master with a background of software development and testing with 20+ experience in IT and especially more than 5 years' experience in SCRUM and Agile. I have a proven record of implementing and supporting the Scrum framework, build trust and empower teams to stimulate innovation while producing viable increments on time.

I have helped multiple in-house and offshore teams to achieve project goals by removing any impediments, building a safe and open space for members to innovate, improve and learn how to self-manage. I am positive, self-motivated, an excellent communicator and passionate about my work.

I am currently looking for a company that provides a challenging environment and a chance for personal and professional growth.

Position	Company	Start	End
		Month	Month
Scrum Master	Lionbridge Technologies (CLS-4Text)	Jan 2019	now
Digital Marketing Technology Lead	Lionbridge Technologies	May 2013	Jan 2019
Business System Development Lead	Lionbridge Technologies	Oct 2005	May 2013

Key Skills

Servant Leader - Agile Coaching and mentoring - Solid interpersonal skills - Software Development - Process Improvement - AzureDevOps - Graylog - Customer Relationships - Problem Solving - Microsoft Azure

Certifications

- PSM1
- Lean 6 Sigma yellow belt
- Agile Development in Practice
- Adam Developer Certification

Education

Degree in computer science | CDI (College of business and technology)

Professional Experience

Scrum Master

Lionbridge Technologies (CLS-4Text)

Berlin | January 2019 to January 2021

Responsibilities

As a Scrum Master, I helped and coached offshore teams on a new application for Project Managers and Senior Management to track projects and report essential KPIs. I worked closely with the Product Managers on the planning and design of the system. My role also included the use of Agile principles and tools to support collaboration and communication.

Experience:

- -Facilitate all Scrum events and success for the Scrum team
- Coach, motivate and support the development team
- -Support Product Managers for planning, prioritizing, curating backlog, managing risks
- Improve development processes using Agile principles
- Create and monitor various KPIs for Stakeholders
- Support adoption of MS AzureDevops for development cycle management
- Support problem solving when it occurs
- Help team to set up MS Azure and create KPIs to monitor performances

Accomplishments

- Participated in planning, designing and developing a new web application to improve the Project Management processes
- Participated in creating KPIs, dashboards and various alerts in Graylog and Microsoft Azure
- Oversaw the training of the team to learn new technologies
- Collaborated with internal teams to initiate and implement procedural changes and customized workflows
- Participated in the setup of Microsoft Azure solution
- Participated in the setup of Microsoft AzureDevops solution for development processes and releases

Digital Marketing Technology Lead

Lionbridge Technologies

Dublin | May 2013 to January 2019

Responsibilities

As Digital Marketing Technology Lead / Scrum Master, my role was to lead teams in Dublin and Mumbai on various development projects using Agile principles. The teams worked on all aspects of the development project life cycle from writing technology specifications, design, development and implementation. Another part of my role was to provide support to the sales team regarding technology used and possible improvements of assets.

Experience:

- Support end to end project development & client engagement during the project
- Sales support on all aspects of marketing technology

- Manage client relationships and serve as primary day-to-day contact for internal and external clients
- -Support teams of developers on various web and desktop applications
- Work on new service offerings for Lionbridge
- Work closely with various external digital agencies
- -Coach an off-shore team
- Leading research across the Digital Marketing sphere, from technology to marketing trends
- Create quotes and LOEs for development projects

Accomplishments

- Implementation and operationalisation of a new services offering (email development and DX reports)
- Participate in a technology and process discovery for a major client
- Oversee the development of Heuristic analysis
- Collaborate with internal teams to initiate and implement procedural changes and customized workflows
- Organize and participate in client meetings and clients demos
- Received Adam developer certification
- Create documentation on email localisation best practices

Business System Development Lead

Lionbridge Technologies

Dublin | Oct 2005 to May 2013

Responsibilities

As Business System Development Lead, my role was to lead a team of developers on various web and desktop development projects focusing on improving internal processes. With the help of the management team I created an off-shore team based in Mumbai to help with the growing demand for new tools for process improvements around project management, localisation engineering and desktop publishing. Around that time I also help with the planning of a new offering around email development for marketing campaigns for multiple markets.

Experience:

- Lead end to end project development & client engagementt during the project
- Drive process improvement projects
- Offshore team leading & training
- Supervise, motivate and set goals for development team
- Manage client relationships and serve as primary day-to-day contact for internal and external clients
- Conduct interviews for new hires
- Improving/designing team processes and developing new business streams
- Helping to create and roll-out multiple process iterations and infrastructure updates
- Create quotes and LOEs for development projects

Accomplishments

- Build an off-shore development team in Mumbai
- Lead the creation of a bug/query management system used by clients, vendors and internal staff
- Leading research for process improvements on dozens of new tools and processes
- Participate in the creation of a new service offering with a large client
- Six Sigma green belt certification
- Maintained a long lasting, successful partnership with several client teams